{
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "Which process in plants converts light energy into chemical energy?",
      "options": ["Respiration", "Photosynthesis", "Transpiration", "Chemosynthesis"],
      "correctAnswer": "b"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "Which pigment in plants is primarily responsible for absorbing sunlight during photosynthesis?",
      "options": ["Chlorophyll", "Carotene", "Xanthophyll", "Anthocyanin"],
      "correctAnswer": "a"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "In which part of the plant does photosynthesis mainly occur?",
      "options": ["Roots", "Flowers", "Leaves", "Stem"],
      "correctAnswer": "c"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "Which gas is used by plants during the process of photosynthesis?",
      "options": ["Oxygen", "Carbon dioxide", "Nitrogen", "Hydrogen"],
      "correctAnswer": "b"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "What is the main product of photosynthesis?",
      "options": ["Water", "Glucose", "Oxygen", "Carbon dioxide"],
      "correctAnswer": "b"
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "What is the role of stomata in plant nutrition?",
      "options": ["Absorbing nutrients from the soil", "Regulating water loss", "Gas exchange", "All of the above"],
      "correctAnswer": "c"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "Which part of the leaf contains the most chloroplasts?",
      "options": ["Spongy mesophyll", "Palisade mesophyll", "Epidermis", "Xylem"],
      "correctAnswer": "b"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "Plants obtain nitrogen from the soil in the form of:",
      "options": ["Nitrogen gas", "Ammonia", "Nitrates", "Nitrites"],
      "correctAnswer": "c"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "Which type of plants can fix nitrogen from the atmosphere?",
      "options": ["Leguminous plants", "Non-leguminous plants", "Carnivorous plants", "Hydrophytes"],
      "correctAnswer": "a"
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "Which element is essential for the synthesis of proteins in plants?",
      "options": ["Calcium", "Nitrogen", "Potassium", "Magnesium"],
      "correctAnswer": "b"
    },

    {
      "id": 11,
      "question": "Which type of teeth in humans is primarily responsible for tearing food?",
      "options": ["Molars", "Premolars", "Canines", "Incisors"],
      "correctAnswer": "c"
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "question": "Where does most of the digestion and absorption of nutrients occur in the human digestive system?",
      "options": ["Stomach", "Small intestine", "Large intestine", "Mouth"],
      "correctAnswer": "b"
    },
    {
      "id": 13,
      "question": "Which enzyme in the saliva breaks down starch into simpler sugars?",
      "options": ["Pepsin", "Lipase", "Amylase", "Trypsin"],
      "correctAnswer": "c"
    },
    {
      "id": 14,
      "question": "Which part of the human body produces bile, which helps in the digestion of fats?",
      "options": ["Pancreas", "Liver", "Stomach", "Small intestine"],
      "correctAnswer": "b"
    },
    {
      "id": 15,
      "question": "What is the primary function of carbohydrates in human nutrition?",
      "options": ["Muscle repair", "Energy production", "Hormone production", "Bone strengthening"],
      "correctAnswer": "b"
    },
    {
      "id": 16,
      "question": "Which vitamin helps in the absorption of calcium and is essential for healthy bones?",
      "options": ["Vitamin C", "Vitamin D", "Vitamin A", "Vitamin K"],
      "correctAnswer": "b"
    },
    {
      "id": 17,
     "question": "What is the main function of proteins in the human body?",
     "options": ["Provide energy", "Build and repair tissues", "Store vitamins", "Improve digestion"],
     "correctAnswer": "b"
    },
    {
      "id": 18,
     "question": "Which macronutrient is stored in the body for long-term energy reserves?",
     "options": ["Proteins", "Fats", "Carbohydrates", "Vitamins"],
     "correctAnswer": "b"
    },
    {
      "id": 19,
      "question": "What is the function of the large intestine in the digestive system?",
      "options": ["Nutrient absorption", "Water absorption and waste formation", "Breakdown of fats", "Protein digestion"],
      "correctAnswer": "b"
    },
    {
      "id": 20,
      "question": "Which of the following vitamins is water-soluble?",
      "options": ["Vitamin A", "Vitamin C", "Vitamin D", "Vitamin E"],
      "correctAnswer": "b"
    }
  ]
}
